Guide to the Yale Collection of German Literature Manuscript Miscellany
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- U
  - UNIDENTIFIED
    - Note reporting on politcal meeting about the King of Frankfurt, undated; Unidentified; 1 item (1 p.); 10 x 13 cm. (Box GROUP 29, Folder F-2)
    - "Elegy on the Death of Werter", [ca. 1785]; Unidentified; 1 item (2 p.); 33 cm. (Box GROUP 29, Folder F-3)
      Poem, manuscript, concerning Goethe's Sorrows of Young Werther.
      Accession: 19980319-g
    - Papers relating to Johann Wolfgang von Goethe, 1880-1925, undated; Unidentified; 4 items. (Box GROUP 29, Folder F-4)
      Papers include one autograph manuscript horoscope, in an unidentified hand, for Goethe on his birthdate; two family trees of the Textor and Goethe families, one autograph manuscript, dated 1880 and in an unidentified hand, and one typed (copy); and one typescript letter, dated 1925, from the Goethe Museum in Frankfurt to Mrs. Hans Textor.
      Accession: 41069
    - Notes on philosophy, [circa 1950-2000]; 1 item (3 l.) 28 cm. (Box GROUP 29, Folder F-5)
      Manuscript in an unidentified hand.
  - UNTERMEYER, JEAN STARR, 1886-1970
    - "Remember me to the three children I love best", [19]47 Dec 18; Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1886-1970; 1 item (1 p.); 28 cm. (Box GROUP 7, Folder F-1)
      Poem, typescript carbon, corrected, with "Finney Farm, Croton" at head.
    - "The Call", undated; Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1886-1970; 1 item (1 p.); 28 cm. (Box GROUP 7, Folder F-2)
      Poem, typescript, signed. Translation of "Berufung," dated 1913 on verso, by Uriel Birnbaum. Removed from Eine Auswahl by Uriel Birnbaum (Amsterdam: Erasmus Buchhandlung, 1957).
    - "The Gift Unlooked-For", undated; Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1886-1970; 1 item (1 p.); 28 cm. (Box GROUP 7, Folder F-3)
      Poem, typescript, corrected and signed. Translation of poem by Uriel Birnbaum.
      Removed from Eine Auswahl by Uriel Birnbaum (Amsterdam: Erasmus Buchhandlung, 1957).
  - URZIDIL, JOHANNES, 1896-1970
    - Letters: Apartment 6-E, 83-39 116th Street, Richmond Hill 18, New York, to Hans Demetz, 1962-63; Urzidil, Johannes, 1896-1970; 2 items. (Box GROUP 6, Folder F-1)
      Two ALS, dated 1962 Dec 19 and 1963 Dec 27. In German.
      Accession: 19911210-a
    - Letters: to Jean [Starr Untermeyer], 1958, undated; Urzidil, Johannes, 1896-1970; 2 items. (Box GROUP 6, Folder F-2)
      One ALS, dated 1958 Mar 15, expressing gratitude for a generous appraisal of an unidentified book, and one undated postcard, holograph, signed.
      Removed from unidentified book.
- V
  - VAGTS, ALFRED, 1892-
    - Correspondence about Dadaism, 1957 March-November; Vagts, Alfred, 1892-; 6 items. (Box GROUP 50, Folder F-1)
      Correspondence with Letitia Chamberlain and Lee J. Lockwood, accompanied by copies of excerpts from Vagts's diary, typescript, about Dadaism.
      Former call number: Zg20 Mss V132
    - "Notebook of Alfred Vagts, Yale Graduate School, 1924-1925, first post-World War I exchange student from Germany", undated; Vagts, Alfred, 1892-; 1 item ([25] l.); 28 cm. (Box GROUP 50, Folder F-2)
      Typed transcript, photocopy.
      Title from caption.
- W
  - WERNER, CARL, 1919-
    - "Spiessegesellen tragen graue Haut", undated; Werner, Carl, 1919-; 1 item (42 leaves); 30 cm. (Box GROUP 23, Folder F-1)
      Poem, typescript carbon, corrected. Accompanied by a descriptive summary, typescript carbon, and a note with Werner's address.
  - WILDER, THORNTON, 1897-1975
    - Letters: to Hermann Broch, 1939-42; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; 7 items. (Box GROUP 11, Folder F-1)
      Seven ALS discussing work, the theater and literature, including the work of Frederico García Lorca, Robert Musil and Franz Blei, and mentioning Mabel Dodge Luhan, "Dr. Preminger," "Dr. Horch," James Joyce and others.
      Accession: 19950701-hx
- Y
  - YALE UNIVERSITY. DEPT. OF GERMANIC LANGUAGES
    - "German Syllabus: for German 15 and German 25: 55/6 / prepared by members of the German Department, Yale University", [1955-1956?]; Yale University. Department of Germanic Languages; 1 v. (140 l.); 29 cm. (Box GROUP 55, Folder F-1)
      Textbook, typescript mimeograph, for a beginning course in German, based on United States Armed Forces intensive language training.
      Former call number: Zg20 Mss Y17
      Accession: 46324
- Z
  - ZWEIG, STEFAN, 1881-1942
    - Letters: to Carl F. Schreiber, 1932, 1934; Zweig, Stefan, 1881-1942; 2 items. (Box GROUP 24, Folder F-1)
      Two TLS, dated 1932 Jun 8 and 1934 Jun 23. With two carbons of letters from Schreiber to Zweig, dated 1932 May 19 and 1932 Aug 17, and one TL from Zweig's secretary to Schreiber, dated 1932 Feb 27, enclosing typescript copy of letter, dated 1930 Apr 30, from F. W. Kaufmann to Zweig.
    - "Vorbeigehen an Weininger", undated; Zweig, Stefan, 1881-1942; 1 item (5 leaves); 29 cm. (Box GROUP 24, Folder F-2)
      Holograph manuscript, corrected, concerning Otto Weininger.
    - "Kleine Reise nach Brasilien", 1936; Zweig, Stefan, 1881-1942; 1 item (52 p.); 26 cm. (Box GROUP 24, Folder F-3)
      Autograph manuscript of an account of the author's voyage to Brazil.
    - Preface to "The Jewish Contribution to Civilization", 1939; Zweig, Stefan, 1881-1942; 1 item (52 p.); 26 cm. (Box GROUP 24, Folder F-4)
      Typescript, corrected. Accompanied by 3 TLS to Charles A. Stonehill relating to the translation of the preface into English.